proactiveinvestors.com.au 2019-04-17

# Proactive Investors Limited - Leading source of Financial News, Investor Forums, CEO Interviews, Financial Columnists, Stock Information - Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

Proactive Investors Australia Pty Ltd  ACN 132 787 654 **(the “Company,” “we” or “us”)** respects your privacy and undertakes to protect any personal information entrusted to it. This document sets out our Privacy Policy commitment in respect of personal information that you may provide to us. Generally, you may visit our Site without giving us any information about yourself (but we may use Cookies to gather information about you, even if you do not register as a user – please see the section on Cookies below). There are times when we may need to obtain information from you through a registration process in order to provide certain services. Below we describe how we gather and use data. If you are not comfortable with any of the practices or policies described in our privacy policy, we ask that you discontinue use of our Site. Please ensure that you read this privacy policy and the associated Terms & Conditions. Our privacy policy may change from time to time, so please revisit this page frequently to remain fully informed of our latest practices and policies.

**Consent**

By using this Site, you consent to our collection, use and disclosure of any personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We may, at any time, to modify or update this Privacy Policy. Every time you use our site as an unregistered user, your continued use of the Site constitutes your acceptance and agreement to the then current version of this Privacy Policy, whether or not you have read it at that time. It is up to you to regularly check this Privacy Policy to update yourself of any changes. If you are a registered user, we will notify you of any changes to this Privacy Policy by emailing you a link to the revised Privacy Policy to the email address you have given us. Your continued use of the Site following our sending of such a notification constitutes acceptance by you of the new Privacy Policy.

**What is Personal information**

When we refer to personal information we mean information or an opinion about you, from which you are, or may reasonably be, identified.

This information may include (but is not limited to) your name, date of birth, email address, phone number, address and occupation.

We do not collect sensitive information about you (such as information about your religion, health, trade union membership, political opinion, sexual preference or criminal record). We will only collect sensitive information about you with your consent.

**How we use your personal information**

The Company collects, records, retains and uses your personal information only for legitimate business purposes; including but not limited to (i) to provide, administer, support, improve and obtain feedback on our services and to send you information that you have requested; (ii) to comply with applicable laws, enforce our Terms of Use or other agreements; and to protect the rights or property of the Company, our users and others; (iii) to solicit your opinions about our services or to introduce new services; and/or (iv) for quality control, regulatory, and monitoring purposes.  
We may also use your contact details to occasionally send you information about our partners that may be of interest to you. You may opt-out of this in your user profile.

**When we may disclose your personal information**

**To Third Parties:**

We will not sell or rent your personal information to third parties. We do aggregate certain user data to create profiles of "typical" users, which aggregate data may be disclosed to applicable third parties. We will disclose information when required to do so by law, in response to a request from a law enforcement agency, Court, Tribunal or authority or otherwise with your prior written consent.

**To Others in Your Own Organization:**

If you use any of our services through your employer, then we may pass certain information to your employer regarding your use of such services where your employer has a legitimate reason to receive such information, as determined by us in our sole discretion. Similarly, if you are the point contact person in your organization for a service, we may pass your contact details to those in your organization for this purpose. By providing us with your personal information, you consent to us disclosing your information to such persons or entities without obtaining your consent on a case by case basis.

**To Recipients Located Outside Australia:**

We may from time to time transfer personal information outside Australia in accordance with the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth)  to countries whose privacy laws do not provide the same level of protection as Australia's privacy laws. For example, we may transfer your personal information to the Asia-Pacific, European Union or the United States of America. We may also use cloud storage and IT servers that are located off shore.

By providing us with your personal information, you consent to us disclosing your information to entities located outside Australia and, when permitted by law to do so, on the basis that we are not required to take such steps as are reasonable to ensure that any overseas recipient complies with Australian privacy laws in relation to your information.

**How we collect your personal information**

**Information Collected Through Our Services:**

If you choose to register for any of our services, we will gather information from the registration process. We collect information about your use of our services, such as generic types of data accessed, times and volume of use of the services and traffic data. Traffic data includes logs, details of networks, data and systems accessed details of the sender and recipients of messages sent over our services, times and location of log on or access, duration of sessions, clickstream and similar usage or system data. Before you register with us, we do not gather any personally identifiable information about you. If you do not provide the information requested by us, we may not be able to provide you with our services.

If you provide personal information to us about someone else, you must ensure that you are entitled to disclose that information to us and that, without us taking any further steps required by privacy laws, we may collect, use and disclose such information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. For example, you should take reasonable steps to ensure that the individual concerned is aware of the various matters detailed in this Privacy Policy. The individual must also provide the consents set out in this Privacy Policy in respect of how we deal with their personal information.

**Information Collected Through Cookies:**

In order to personalize and enhance your experience on our Site, we may also collect information through “cookies.” Cookies are small strings of text sent by our Site to your browser and then stored by your browser on your computer’s hard drive. Cookies enable us to collect information about how our services are used. They can record information about your visit to the website, allowing it to remember you the next time you visit and provide a more meaningful experience. A cookie is 'personal information'. Until you have registered with us, the cookie will only track general usage patterns and technical information about your computer type and will not be used to identify you individually. After registration, cookies will be used to collect information on an aggregate basis, to track the readership of stories and usage of our products, to analyze traffic patterns on our sites and to provide anonymous reporting of usage. You can turn off the ability to receive cookies by adjusting the browser in your computer. However, you should note that if you do so, it might materially distort the quality of service and data you receive. Therefore, you do so at your own risk.

**Information Collected Through Advertising:**

Where advertising is served on the Site, there may be cookies used to collect technical information and generic usage information. However, third party advertisers will not be able to relate such information to you as an individual without your prior consent. However, please note that by interacting with an advertiser, you are thereby providing consent to data collection by that advertiser.

**Information Collected Through Digital Signatures/Certificates:**

If the product you are using has digital certificates/certificate signatures, then your name and related details may be displayed as part of any certificate issued to you. It will be seen by those to whom your certificate or signature is presented or who rely on your certificate or signature. Your details may also need to be entered into a related status directory of certificates issued.

**Direct Marketing**

From time to time we may use your personal information to provide you with current information about our partners that may be of interest to you, changes to our organisation or new products or services being offered by us or any company we are associated with. By providing us with your personal information, you consent to us using your information to contact you on an ongoing basis for this purpose, including by mail, email, SMS, social media and telephone.

If you do not wish to receive marketing information, you may at any time decline to receive such information by contacting our Privacy Contacts using the contact details below. We will not charge you for giving effect to your request and will take all reasonable steps to meet your request at the earliest possible opportunity.

**How we protect your information**

We use commercially reasonable efforts to provide security safeguards to protect your personal information, such as firewall protection on our servers to prevent unauthorized access to any information we may store. We will also take reasonable steps to protect any personal information from misuse, loss and unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. Although these measures are typically effective, use of the Internet and related computer systems are inherently vulnerable to unauthorized access or “hacking.” No guarantee can be given to ensure that information you provide to us will not be accessed by unauthorized persons. When the information is no longer needed for any purpose for which the information may be used or disclosed, it will be destroyed or permanently de-identified.

**Links to third party websites**

Our Site may offer links to other websites, which may have information policies and practices different from ours. We do not control and are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of any third party sites.

**Interception of mail**

We may reject, delay or remove content from emails which have a nature, content or attachments which, in our sole discretion, may (x) disrupt our systems or pose security issues such as viruses, or (y) be offensive, unwanted or constitute spam. In certain circumstances, this may result in "innocent" emails being affected.

**Updating your personal information**

It is important that the personal information we hold about you is accurate and up to date. From time to time we may ask you to inform us if any of your personal information has changed.

If you consider that any information we hold about you is incorrect, you should contact us to have it updated. We will generally rely on you to assist us in informing us if the information we hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete.

**Access to your personal information**

We will provide you with access to the personal information we hold about you, subject to limited exceptions in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) as outlined below. You may request access to any of the personal information we hold about you at any time. You may also view your personal information at any time by logging in to your account page.

**Denied access to personal information**

There may be situations where we are not required to provide you with access to your personal information. For example, such a situation would be information relating to an existing or anticipated legal proceeding with you, or if your request is vexatious. An explanation will be provided to you if we deny you access to your personal information we hold.

**Further information and complaints**

You may request further information about the way we manage your personal information or lodge a complaint by contacting our Privacy Officer(s) on the contact details below.

We will deal with any complaint by investigating the complaint and providing a response to the complainant within 15 business days, provided that we have all necessary information and have completed any investigation required. In cases where further information, assessment or investigation is required, we will seek to agree alternative time frames with you.

You may request further information about the way we manage your personal information or lodge a complaint by contacting our Privacy Officer(s) on the contact details below:

The Privacy Officer

John Phillips

55 Mountain Street, Ultimo, Sydney, NSW 2007

action@proactiveinvestors.com

We will deal with any complaint by investigating the complaint and providing a response to the complainant within 15 business days, provided that we have all necessary information and have completed any investigation required. In cases where further information, assessment or investigation is required, we will seek to agree alternative time frames with you.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on October 2016.
